立法會主席。
Our first report.
發言，石禮謙議員。
Our first report on the conclusions and recommendations.
主席， on behalf of the Public Accounts Committee.
我有榮耀呈報報告號碼68。
On chapter one, on government support and monitoring of charities.
和章四， on provision of district council funds for community involvement projects.
這是委員會的第二份報告，應對直接審計報告號碼68。
會就政府帳目委員會第六十八A號報告書向本會發言，石阿軒兒。
and land allocation work relating to charitable organisations and their fundraising activities.
它 contains our conclusions and recommendations on Chapter One on government support and monitoring of charities.
There is no overall statutory scheme for the registration and regulation of charities in Hong Kong.
This is report number 68, which focuses on the monitoring of charitable fundraising activities, was tabled in the council in July last year.
在2013，，律法改革委員會發表一份報告，關於慈善機構，提出18項建議，以改善慈善機構的透明度和可追蹤性。
As advised by the secretary for home affairs, at least nine bureaux and quite a number of executive departments are currently involved in the legislation licensing.
Effective performance of its role.
Tax-exempt status of charities effectively.
活動或開支係與佢哋嘅慈善目的相適應嘅。
13 of them are related to the regulation and monitoring of charities.
bearing in mind the I.R.D. main duties is to administer tax-related matters.
HAB is still coordinating comments from relevant bureaux and departments.
它不構成該組織作為慈善組織的正式登記。
The Home Affairs Bureau was tasked to coordinate comments from the relevant bureau and departments for consideration on the way forward.
The committee expresses grave concern and dissatisfaction and finds it unacceptable about the IRD's inadequacies and limitations in ascertaining whether charity.
委員會強烈敦促行政局審視哪個局或部門更合適，負責總體規管及監察慈善機構的運作。
The committee urges HAB to expedite the consultation process, with a view to formulating a substantive report to the Commission's recommendation as soon as possible.
The committee expresses grave concern and dissatisfaction, and finds it unacceptable that more than four years after the publication of the committee's committee's report on charities.
Furthermore, IRD had not acted proactively to review the existing provisions of the Inland Revenue Ordinance regarding tax-exempt status of charities, and to address its limitation in administering.
Furthermore, the committee stresses the inland revenue department plays a vital and unique role in recognising tax exempt status of charities and reviewing their accounts to ensure their eligibility for tax exempt purpose.
委員會表達深切 concern，，即係在現有的規管框架下，，組織的税收豁免地位，根據《內地税收條例》第88條，由税務處認定為慈善機構，但。
IRD is strongly urged to conduct more frequent reviews on the annual accounts of tax-exempt charities. Consider setting up clear guidelines in administering the tax-exempt status of charities, and review sections 88 of the Inland Revenue to enhance the.
其特質和情況。
There are still grey areas in respect of the provision.
Operation of catering facilities in the new headquarters of this grantee.
或私有條約地價，以零或 concess or concessionary premium。
The canteen in the headquarters was open for public use since 1996, which is against the provision of the land lease.
而家地產部門發出一個協議，在2014年7月，劃定地產部門和支援部門之間的責任。
It is important that district councils should ensure transparency and accountability in their consideration and approval of community involvement projects, which involve public money.
In the monitoring role, in enforcing relevant lease conditions and other implementation difficulties, the land department is urged to review and improve this protocol.
The report number 68, having reviewed the administration's responses, the committee decided to invite the relevant bureaux and departments for a public hearing, giving them a chance to explain the issues in more detail.
Have been managed by two organisations without any delegation of agreements since 2006 and 2007 respectively, which undermine the accountability of these two organisations to the Chinese Temple Committee.
The committee also expresses grave concern and dissatisfaction and finds it unacceptable about the inadequacies in the regulation of the Chinese tempo by the Chinese Tempoes Committee. As an example, Mr. President, is that the two tempos.
Mr. President, for the Lands Department, the committee expresses grave concern and finds it again unacceptable that the department have failed to monitor the application and proper use of income generated from hostile hotel service residence on sites granted by way.
The committee expresses serious dismay and finds it unacceptable that the HAB, as the supporting government bureau for monitoring the operation of a grantee since 2000, has failed to properly manage the subvention reduction arrangement and monitor the.
Operation of income generation facilities of this grantee on the site, the committee expresses alarm and strong resentment, and finds it unacceptable that the HAB and the social welfare department have not exercised effective monitoring on the.
係。
質詢。
第一項則信物美娟儀。
內務部被敦促實施措施，以改善情況。
Enhance the management of conflicts of interest in accordance with the standing order of each district council.
最後，我 wish to record my appreciation and contributions of the contributions made by members of the committee. Our gratitude goes to the witnesses who attended the hearings.
Including reminding district council members to declare their interests where appropriate, reminding chairpersons to rule on conflict of interest declared by members at meeting, and recording the rulings as well as their rationale in the minutes of the meeting.
Now I turn to Chapter Four. For Chapter Four on the provision of district council funds for community involvement projects, the committee wrote in May last year to the administration, requesting for written responses to a series of questions on issues raised in this Chapter Four of.
委員會表達深切 concern 滿於關於不一致性和變異性，橫跨不同地區議會在管理社區參與項目時，而每個地區議會都給予一定程度的靈活性，以制定規則和工作程序，以適應。
委員會也表達了極大的滿意，並認為不接受有關不規則和不足之處，就關於區議會成員的利害關係聲明和其委員會及工作小組的聲明。HAD被敦促採取措施以加強。
Help by the committee. I would also like to express our gratitude to the director of audit and his colleague for their unfailing report. Last but not the least, I like to thank the secretariat for their usual manner in providing the usual backup for the committee. Thank you, Mr.